<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>R on r-tastic</title>
    <link>/categories/r/</link>
    <description>Recent content in R on r-tastic</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/r/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring London Crime with R heat maps</title>
      <link>/post/exploring-london-crime-with-r-heat-maps/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/exploring-london-crime-with-r-heat-maps/</guid>
      <description>Recently, I had a real pleasure to work with various types of data pulled from public APIs, one of them being data.police.uk API. Oh, those hours of pure intellectual exploration it’s given me! I have a soft spot for crime data and I explored it using heat maps in the past. Apart from checking and visualising stats for the new area in London we just moved to, it made me think more about good and better ways of presenting complex and multidimensional information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First post in new r-tastic</title>
      <link>/post/first-post-in-new-r-tastic/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/first-post-in-new-r-tastic/</guid>
      <description>OK, it had to happen and here it is: I moved my old r-tastic blog to blogdown and I’m not going to look back :) There are numerous resources that will:
 highlight the advantages of using blogdown with Hugo over other static site generators, such as Jekyll (my previous choice)
 explain how to set everything up (there are some excellent resources here, here or here) or
 deploy your site (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prime hints for running a data project in R</title>
      <link>/post/prime-hints/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/prime-hints/</guid>
      <description>I’ve been asked more and more for hints and best practices when working with R. It can be a daunting task, depending on how deep or specialised you want to be. So I tried to keep it as balanced as I could and mentioned point that definitely helped me in the last couple of years. Finally, there’s lots (and I mean, LOTS) of good advice out there that you should definitely check out - see some examples in the Quick Reference section below.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>End of Year thoughts</title>
      <link>/post/end-of-year-thoughts/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/end-of-year-thoughts/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes it&amp;rsquo;s worth making New Year resolutions&amp;hellip; A year ago I made one for 2017 to start an R blog using RMarkdown and Jekyll static sites. At the time, I didn&amp;rsquo;t even know git that well, had no clue what static sites are and was mostly oblivious to the rich and vibrant R community on Twitter. Fast-forward one year and&amp;hellip; the picture couldn&amp;rsquo;t be any more different! I&amp;rsquo;d like to share my thoughts on writing this blog (and data science blog in general) and how it taught me about getting stuff done.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Star Wars Vs Star Trek Word Battle</title>
      <link>/post/star-wars-vs-star-trek-word-battle/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/star-wars-vs-star-trek-word-battle/</guid>
      <description>It will go without saying that I’m super excited about the premiere of another Star Wars movie and I’m not an exception. This, together with with Piotr Migdal’s challenge posted on Data Science PL group on Facebook where he suggested comparing word frequencies between two different sources. It didn’t take me long to decide what source to choose! So in this short kand sweer blogpost I’m comparing word frequencies between two movie scripts: “Star Wars: The New Hope” (1977) and “Star Trek: The Motion Picture” (1979).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scraping online table with info on R datasets</title>
      <link>/post/scraping-online-table-with-info-on-r-datasets/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/scraping-online-table-with-info-on-r-datasets/</guid>
      <description>It’s a very quick post on how to get a list of datasets available from within R with their basic description (what package they can be found in, number of observations and variables). It always takes me some time to find the right dataset to showcase whatever process or method I’m working with, so this was really to make my life easier. So! I’m going to scrape the table with a list of R datasets from here using rvest and xml2 packages:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amazon reviews wordcloud</title>
      <link>/post/amazon-reviews-word-cloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/amazon-reviews-word-cloud/</guid>
      <description>In the last month I discovered two things that changed my life: audiobooks and Yuval Harari. The former completely transformed my daily commute, the latter changed the way I think about the surrounding world (with more appreciation for history and politics, to say the least). The cocktail of the two made my brain cells sing.
Harari published two books in the last three years: Sapiens: A Brief History of Humankind and more recently: Homo Deus: A Brief History of Tomorrow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Did Disney Princesses distort girl names in USA?</title>
      <link>/post/did-disney-princesses-distort-girl-names-in-usa/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/did-disney-princesses-distort-girl-names-in-usa/</guid>
      <description>My goal is to analyse how frequency of names found among Disney female characters changed over time in the US. Specifically, I want to see if the movie release had any impact on their popularity. For this purpose, I will use babynames dataset that is available on CRAN.
The idea for the exercise was inspired by Sean Kross’ blog post
Short description of the dataset from CRAN package description
The SSA baby names data comes from social security number (SSN) applications.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>